Aw.
什么嘛
Are you already turning back?
你们要回去了吗？
Who's there?
是谁？
She's emitting such an intense aura… Who is this girl?
这个散发着奇妙压迫感的 少女是怎么回事？
Rud, this is bad!
路德 大事不妙了！
Oh, dear.
搞什么？
Did I set it so that Dark Skeletons would continue to spawn?
这里的设定 是会继续出现黑暗骷髅吗？
"Set"?
“设定”？
If four of them attack at once…
在这边一次遭到四只攻击的话…
In one hit…
居然一击就打倒了
I didn't expect
没想到居然会出现魔王等级的守护者
Demon-lord-class?
魔王等级？
I thought I'd already disabled that.
那个会出现黑暗骷髅的设定
Surrender yourself to my Demon Eye!
屈服于我的魔眼吧！
What's with this ridiculously powerful magic?
这强得离谱的魔力是怎么回事？
But I can still handle this much.
不过这种程度我还撑得下去
You actually managed to get out of that without a status ailment.
居然有人可以在接了那一招后 还没陷入异常状态
God's skill is indeed something.
神之技能果然不好对付
Are you the guardian of this labyrinth?
你就是这个迷宫的守护者吗？
Correct.
没错
But you don't seem intimidated by me at all.
不过你看到我 竟然一点都不感到害怕呀
After all, you look like a cute girl.
毕竟你的外表就是个可爱的女孩啊
"Cute"?
我很可爱吗？
My, you have such a way with words.
这话真让人高兴
Don't be fooled, Rud!
别被她骗了 路德
She's a 300-year-old granny!
这家伙可是个超过300岁的老太婆啊
Silence, Marius!
别给我多嘴 玛里乌斯！
You are but a fallen demon lord!
你不过是个吊车尾的魔王罢了！
Marius is my friend.
玛里乌斯是我的同伴
I ask that you do not harm him.
能请你不要伤害他吗？
I see.
原来如此
The fallen demon lord has joined the likes of humans.
吊车尾魔王变成人类的同伴了啊
Not exactly.
我并非想成为人类的同伴
I simply dislike the rest of you demon lords.
我只是讨厌你们这些魔王罢了
I see…
这样啊
Regardless,
不过呢
do not get in my way, Demon Lord Marius.
你可别妨碍我喔 魔王玛里乌斯
You should be aware that you are no match for us.
你应该知道自己赢不过我们吧？
Marius might not be able to take you down on his own,
光靠玛里乌斯一个人 或许真的赢不过你
but you're up against more than just him.
但是现在站在你面前的
And?
那又如何？
Your powers are far from those of a demon lord.
你们每个人的力量 都和我们魔王相差甚远喔
It's true that alone, a human's power is nothing to fear.
一个人类所拥有的力量确实不足为惧
We can't conquer labyrinths alone.
正因为我们无法独自攻略迷宫
That is why we form parties.
所以才会像这样组队互相帮忙
To raid them together?
攻略迷宫啊？
Then let's see if you can defeat me,
那么就让我看看你们 在我这个凯路德迷宫的守护者
the guardian of the Keild Labyrinth, Amon Sloth,
亚蒙·斯萝丝的面前
with your so-called teamwork.
是否也能用所谓的 团队合作来打败我吧
Foolish humans!
愚蠢的人类！
Such powerful magic!
好强大的魔力
We just have to take her on.
只能硬着头皮上了
Sacrificial Shield!
牺牲之盾！
Taunt!
挑衅！
Such power…
好惊人的威力
How dare you hurt my sister!
竟敢伤害姐姐！
She deflected it with a tornado.
居然用龙卷风把攻击弹开了
Even with Taunt,
就算使用了挑衅
she won't focus only on me.
也不会只盯着我这里吗？
Although it's impressive,
虽然确实挺厉害的
this level of attack won't hurt me at all.
但这点程度的攻击根本伤不到我
We'll keep attacking until we do.
那就一直攻击到打到你为止
that kind of attack with wind magic…
我用风魔法就能轻松躲开…
Don't think you can stay in the air forever!
别以为你能一直飘在空中喔
That hurt…
好痛
What a nuisance…
真是个聒噪的女人
Her physical strength is no joke.
她的体能真不是盖的
How do we break through?
该怎么突破才好呢？
Don't worry, I can keep up with her.
别担心 我跟得上她
Is this the extent of your abilities?
你们就这点程度吗？
Taunt!
挑衅！
What's the matter?
怎么啦？
You won't get me with those random attacks.
这样胡乱攻击 可是打不到我的喔
I'm not attacking randomly.
我可不是在胡乱攻击
Flash magic stone!
闪光魔法石！
What's that? It's blinding!
什么东西？好刺眼！
How about that?
怎么样啊？
Is this tempest the result of the magic overflow from earlier?
这股暴风是刚才那些 溢出来的魔力变化而成的吗？
It appears I was careless.
看来是我太大意了
My apologies.
抱歉 各位
Nin, heal everyone up.
妮恩 帮所有人恢复
Got it.
知道了
I'll also cast some buffs. Gather around, everyone.
我会顺便帮大家 施展辅助魔法 靠过来一点
She is on an entirely different level from the monsters we've faced before.
那家伙跟我们以前交手过的魔物
Yeah.
是啊
But as long as we stand united, no monster is our match.
但只要我们同心协力 还是可以打赢她
I will fight hard for Master and Lady Manicia.
为了主人和玛妮西娅大人 我会努力奋战的
Me too.
我也是
Same here, of course.
我当然也是
After all, this is a chance to defeat a demon lord.
毕竟这可是打倒魔王的大好机会啊
Great.
很好 等暴风停下后 我们就上吧
A wolf?
狼？
It looks just like a Fenrir.
简直像芬里尔一样
Marius, can you fight in your monster form?
玛里乌斯能用魔物型态跟她对战吗？
If you don't mind me attacking indiscriminately.
你不介意我敌友不分 随意攻击的话就可以
Suppose it's better for you to stay in this form then.
那你还是保持现在这样比较安心
This will reduce
如此一来
her chances of attacking the other attackers.
就能减少她去袭击攻击手的机会
Next, let's see how long I can hold up
接下来 就看我面对这只大魔兽
against this giant monster.
可以撑到什么时候了
That hardly did any damage to her.
几乎没伤到她
Her fur is as tough as an armor.
她的毛简直坚固得像盔甲
Keep your eyes on me!
别东张西望的！
Those fangs are no joke.
要是被那种獠牙咬到 可不是开玩笑的啊
But her attacks have gotten much simpler.
不过她的攻击方式很单调
My shield force is draining fast…
因为承受了连续攻击 护盾快耗尽了
Prepare to cast long-distance magic.
准备施展远距离魔法
Doesn't seem very effective.
看起来似乎没什么效果
It's a battle against the guardian.
毕竟是与守护者战斗
We've been prepared for this to be a long fight.
我们本来就做好了长期抗战的觉悟
Her attacks are actually getting stronger!
攻击居然变得更沉重了
Dang, I can't catch a break.
可恶 真想找个时机喘口气
Sorry, Rud.
抱歉 路德
Took me some time
为了凝聚力量 稍微花了点时间
You're good, don't worry about it.
没事 你做得很好
He actually cut through that fur armor.
居然能将那宛如盔甲般坚硬的毛切断
As expected of Marius.
不愧是玛里乌斯
Why is she howling?
好惊人的嚎叫
Rud, just in case,
路德 为了以防万一
I can't heal you guys in the meantime, so be careful.
这段期间我无法帮忙恢复伤害 你们小心一点
Got it.
我知道了
Rud, are you okay?
路德 你没事吧？
I'm fine. My shield force seems to be holding up.
没事 护盾看起来还撑得住
As long as I don't go down,
只要我没有倒下
with their strength, we won't lose.
以伙伴们的实力 我们是不会输的
We have to keep pushing through.
得努力撑下去才行
I'll persist until the end.
我会就这样坚持到最后的！
Taunt!
挑衅！
She's resilient.
这家伙还真顽强
But her movements are starting to slow down.
不过她的动作开始变迟钝了
What's going on?
怎么回事？
What's with that green gust?
那阵绿色的风到底是什么？
Whatever it is,
别管那是什么
I'll slice it apart!
看我全部劈开！
Marius!
玛里乌斯！
Judging from that attack,
看那攻击方式
it seems to be a wind barrier that slashes anyone who comes near it.
应该是能用风 把靠近的人斩碎的防护罩吧
The magic stone on her forehead
她额头那个魔石
didn't shine so brightly
在展开防护罩前并没有在闪烁
Maybe if we destroy that stone, we'll be able to defeat her.
或许只要破坏掉那颗魔石 就有办法打败她
But we can't get close to her with that gust.
但是因为那阵风 我们完全无法靠近她啊
After that, we'll attack together.
然后所有人一起攻击
Got it.
我知道了
In the radiance of the holy light,
在神圣的光芒之下
the power of darkness…
黑暗之力啊…
We need to buy time for Nin.
我们要帮妮恩争取时间
Quietly emerging within the unseen brilliance of white waves…
于白色波动中静静浮现
It's getting hard to breathe
因为强风不断吹过来
because of the wind.
变得有些难以呼吸
Just that alone is hard enough,
光是这样就够难受的了
and we've still got to deal with the wind blades.
还一直有风刃砍过来
This is hell…
简直像地狱一样痛苦
With the light of mercy shining into the darkness…
伴随着照进黑暗的耀眼慈悲…
-I have to hold on. -Dissipate in silence.
-即便如此 我也要撑下去！ -寂静地消散吧
Prepare yourselves!
彻底做好防护
We'll hold on.
如果遭到攻击…
She's not letting us get closer.
是不想让我们靠近她吗？
Render it all void!
化为无力吧！
Cease your pointless struggle.
不要再做无谓的挣扎了！
I've removed the wind barrier.
我把风的防护罩解除了
Destroy the stone now!
趁现在把那颗魔石破坏掉！
All right!
好！
You won't escape!
不会让你逃跑的！
She blocked all the attacks on the magic stone.
对魔石的攻击都被挡下了啊
But in doing so, she also left her chest vulnerable.
但胸前也因此变得毫无防备
Get her, Rud!
上吧 路德！
My shield force has been depleted by almost 30,000.
我的护盾目前被消耗了将近三万点！
Take this!
接招吧！
Life Conversion!
生命转换！
That's…
那是…
different from a barrier.
跟盔甲不同
That's offensive wind magic!
那是攻击用的风魔法！
Everyone, dodge!
所有人立即离开！
Oh, no!
糟糕！
That's the sound of the shield breaking.
刚才那是护盾破碎的声音
Rud!
路德！
I must hold on…
撑下去
If I use up all my shield force
如果在这里耗尽护盾 导致重伤的话
I'll die!
只有死路一条！
Rud…
路德
Has it stopped?
停下来了吗？
Rud, are you all right?
路德 你没事吧？
Yeah, I barely made it through.
没事 勉强撑过来了
Lilia!
姐姐！
Hang in there!
你们振作一点啊！
Rud…
路德
Thank goodness you two are still alive.
太好了 幸好你们还活着
Luna, Nin,
露娜、妮恩
heal them.
帮他们两个恢复
They'll be killed if she launches another attack.
否则她发动追击的话会被杀掉的
You've used up all your shield force.
你的护盾已经耗尽了
It's too dangerous.
这样太危险了
I can still use my skills without it.
就算没有护盾 我还是可以使用技能
I can still fight.
我还可以继续战斗
Besides, I'm the only one here who can stop her.
而且这里只有我可以挡下她
Got it.
我知道了
Luna. Lily.
露娜、莉莉
Moreover, I'm the one who selfishly
而且任性地说想来这里的人 本来就是我
They came because of me.
既然他们都陪我来了
It's my responsibility to protect all of them.
我就得负起责任保护好大家
I'm feeling the pain without the shield…
因为护盾耗尽 开始感受得到疼痛了
At this rate, I'm going to be crushed!
这样下去会被压扁的！
Wind magic?
是风魔法？
No?
没出现？
She can't use any more magic.
不 是用不出来吗？
She's weak.
她已经变得很虚弱了
We're so close…
差一点就能打倒她了吗？
I hate to say it,
虽然很不甘心 但今天只能先撤退…
I can still fight.
我还可以战斗
Nin, Luna, prepare your magic.
妮恩、露娜 请准备施展魔法
From now on,
接下来我会作为攻击手负责战斗
Lily, what are you saying?
莉莉 你在说什么啊？
I'll use Fusion and take Lilia's place.
我会用融合技能代替姐姐进行战斗
All it takes is a little more and we will defeat her.
既然她已经这么虚弱了
-But… -Rud.
-但是… -路德！
You said you'd listen to my request.
你不是说会答应我的愿望吗？
I can still fight!
我真的还可以战斗！
What a reckless one.
真是个爱乱来的家伙呢
I understand.
我知道了 我会负责挡下攻击的
I'll help too.
我也来帮忙
Let's take her down with all we have!
用尽全力把她打倒吧
Yes!
好的！
I didn't realize how much power I'd lose
没想到失去护盾后
without my shield.
会变得如此使不上力
But,
但是呢
I've got to buy her time.
我得帮忙争取时间才行
Rud!
路德！
Thanks, Nin.
谢了 妮恩
Lily, are you ready?
莉莉 你准备好了吗？
Ready.
我要上了
I'm not done yet.
还没完
Rud!
路德！
Her speed isn't too different from when Lilia's in control,
虽然速度和莉莉亚主导的 融合状态没什么差别
but unlike her,
但是她和莉莉亚不同 动作太单调
They're too predictable.
马上就被对方看透了
Sorry.
不好意思
I'm not used to this body yet.
我还没办法有效地使用这副身体
In that case,
既然如此 就照你平时那样战斗吧
Lilia's out cold anyway.
反正莉莉亚现在也昏过去了
Don't worry about her.
你没必要顾虑她
Fight in your own way.
就照你的风格去战斗吧
My own way?
照我的风格？
I'll buy you time until you get used to it.
在你习惯前 我会努力帮你争取时间
So take your time.
所以你就慢慢准备吧
Got it.
我知道了
Although,
虽然就现在的情况
but my comrade is fighting so hard to change.
但是我的同伴 正为了做出改变而努力奋斗
So, it's my job
那么身为她的同伴
to support her.
就应该助她一臂之力吧
Rud!
路德！
Curses.
可恶 看来现在的我
it's really hard for me to do my job as the tank.
很难尽到肉盾的职责 帮忙争取时间
I think I'm going to pass out from the pain…
就连现在也痛到快昏过去了
No, these are just excuses.
不 这都只是借口罢了
No matter what happens,
不论面临什么状况
it's my job to protect my party.
我都应该保护好自己的同伴！
Marius used mana as his shield force.
玛里乌斯都是把魔力化为护盾来使用
If I do the same,
如果我也能那样
maybe I can continue to fight.
或许就能继续战斗了
Rud, she's heading towards you!
路德 她过去你那里了！
It's not perfect, but it worked.
虽然不是很完美 但还是成功了
Still, this isn't enough.
不过光是现在这样还不够
I need to focus my mana and transform it into my shield force!
我要更努力地感受全身的魔力
I can move just like when I still had my shield force.
身体可以像护盾包覆时一样灵活运动
The pain in my arm is fading too.
手臂的疼痛也减缓了
So that's how you do it.
原来就是这么做的啊
She sped up her attacks.
她的攻击速度变快了
Is she getting anxious?
是开始着急了吗？
Unleash more mana.
再把身上的魔力多释放一些出来
I can move as freely as I did when I had my shield force surrounding me.
现在可以跟有护盾包覆在身上时 一样自在地活动了
Time for the counterattack!
反击时间开始了！
Lily, now!
莉莉 趁现在！
This is different from Lilia.
跟姐姐不同
This is my way of fighting!
这是属于我的战斗方式！
What power!
好强大的威力
Did she enchant the sword with all elements?
是把各种属性的魔法附到剑上了吗？
Let's end it with this!
就用这招一决胜负吧
She's planning to strike with all four elements at once!
她打算一口气 用四种属性魔法砍过去吗？
Lily! Are you okay?
莉莉 你没事吧？
I'm okay…
没事
Thank you, Rud.
谢谢你 路德
That's my line.
这是我该说的话
We won today because of you.
我们今天能赢 都是多亏了你喔
It wasn't just me.
这不是我一个人的功劳喔
Now, take a little break.
现在你就稍微休息一下吧
Amon,
亚蒙 你还想继续战斗吗？
I cannot even move anymore.
我早就已经动不了了好吗？
You put up an excellent fight.
你们真的很厉害呢
I never thought I'd see the day I'd be defeated.
没想到我竟然也有被打败的一天
I'm looking for a magic stone that can grant any wish.
我在找可以实现任何愿望的魔石
Do you know anything about that?
你有没有什么头绪？
Here, take it.
来 拿去吧
Thanks.
谢谢你
Never expected my opponent to thank me. That is a surprise indeed.
想不到对手居然会反过来跟我道谢
Well? Are you not delivering the final blow?
那么你不给我最后一击吗？
Or are you perhaps the type that enjoys tormenting pretty girls?
难道你是以折磨美少女为乐的人吗？
You said you were a demon lord.
你说过自己是魔王吧？
Are there any other demon lords?
除了你以外 还有其他魔王吗？
Of course.
有啊 当然有
Though, I do not know the exact number.
但我也不知道实际上有多少人
What is their objective?
魔王们的目的是什么？
Among demon lords, there is a popular game
魔王们正在玩一种游戏
of how to destroy this world.
那就是找能如何破坏这个世界的方法
And what is your goal?
那么你的目的是什么？
Do you seek to be an enemy of the humans as a demon lord?
是想作为魔王 与人类为敌
Or do you just want to fight strong opponents?
还是单纯想跟强劲的对手战斗？
You have an intention.
你是有什么话想说吗？
Yes.
没错
Speak away.
说说看吧
Will you help us?
你愿意帮助我们吗？
If the demon lords
如果之后 魔王会来招惹人类
I plan to gather forces to resist them.
那我想网罗足以对抗他们的战力
Then simply put a slave bracelet on me and make me obey your command.
那就直接给我戴上奴隶手环
I don't like to force others against their will.
我不喜欢那样强迫别人
That's why I'm asking.
所以我想拜托你帮助我们
An amusing one you are, indeed.
你真是个有趣的家伙呢
Well, I'm not particularly attached to my identity as a demon lord.
反正我也不是很在意魔王这个身份
Rather, since you have extended an invitation,
不如说既然你都愿意接纳我了
I shall gladly become your ally.
那我当然很乐意成为你们的同伴
Thank you.
谢谢你
Now, let's return to the city…
那么我们先回镇上…
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I am tired.
我累了啦
I can't take another step. Carry me.
已经一步都走不动了 抱我回去嘛
Eh?
什么？
And thus,
就这样我们成功说服 凯路德迷宫的守护者
the guardian of Keild Labyrinth, to join our forces.
亚蒙·斯萝丝成为我们的同伴
After that,
后来两大战团再次举办了舞会
And I…
而我…
We've successfully raided Keild Labyrinth.
我们战团成功攻略凯路德迷宫了
Is this the map of the 51st floor?
这就是第51层的地图？
You're kidding!
这不是真的吧
In exchange for this map and information,
我将拿这份地图和情报作为交换
I request an alliance with the two clans.
向两大战团发出同盟申请！
I announced that in front of everyone.
我就这样在众人面前如此宣布
Of course,
当然这次也没对外公布 守护者成为了我们的同伴
After successfully forming an alliance with them,
成功与两大战团结盟后
we embarked on our journey back to Avancia.
我们准备返回阿凡锡亚
I want to see Manicia soon…
好想快点见到玛妮西娅喔
Rud.
路德
Li…
莉…
Shh. You'll wake everyone.
这样会吵醒大家的 请你小声一点
It's nothing. And I told you, didn't I?
那没什么 而且我不是说过了吗？
It was thanks to you…
当时是多亏有你才…
We won because of everyone's efforts.
这次之所以能获胜 是大家的功劳
But it was thanks to you that I could fight until the end.
但是我能战斗到最后是路德的功劳
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'm going back to sleep.
那我回去睡觉了
What was that about?
刚才那是怎么回事？
And she fell asleep right away.
而且她居然马上睡着了！
I'll just have to ask her later what that kiss meant.
只能之后再问她那是什么意思了
I should just sleep…
现在还是先睡觉吧
Rud.
路德
Lilia!
莉莉亚
Did she see that?
难道她看到刚才那一幕了？
Thank you for what you did in the labyrinth.
之前在迷宫战斗时 谢谢你
I heard your voice.
你的声音 我清楚地听到了
That's all.
我只是想告诉你这个而已
Oh… Okay…
哦 好
After arriving in Avancia,
到了阿凡锡亚后
we rushed to Manicia.
我们马上赶往玛妮西娅身边
Manicia, use this magic stone.
玛妮西娅 快用这颗魔石吧
How do you feel?
怎么样？
I feel so much better.
感觉不错 身体也变得轻盈多了
Thank you so much, Miss Amon.
亚蒙小姐
There's not much I can do for you,
虽然我能为亚蒙小姐做的事情不多
into preparing three meals and afternoon tea for you.
以及下午三点的点心 我都会用心准备的
So, please enjoy yourself
所以在这里的期间
during your stay here.
还请你不用客气 尽管吃吧
Being warmly welcomed by such a lovely human is a delight.
能受到你这种可爱人类的盛情款待
And the snacks are delicious too.
而且点心也很好吃
I shall remain in this town for the time being.
我就暂时留在这个镇上打发时间吧